Bella Nicholson

♀ Amsterdam, Netherlands

% bellanich.github.io

in bella-nicholson

O bellanich

American

Resourceful Machine Learning Engineer with 3+ years of experience in a diverse set of organizations, ranging from tech startups and scaleups to an establish tech company. A life-long learner with a passion for optimizing ML models for real-world applications on resource-constrained devices. Actively exploring the implications of efficient edge neural solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer

Brenntag

Mov 2023 - Present

Amsterdam, Netherlands

At the world's leading chemical distributor, I deployed and maintained ML products across 70+ countries. Thus far, I've:

- Migrated a virtual AI assistant (earning €30+ million in annual revenue) to a more cost-effective and secure AWS platform
- Standardized quality controls across 15+ ML project components through the creation of a CLI package prototype

(Junior) AI Consultant

Deloitte Consulting

Sept 2021 - Oct 2023

Amsterdam, Netherlands

As a contracted ML engineer, I optimized and implemented ML solutions for diverse clients, delivering:

- Increased system robustness of a Dutch e-classified ads platform's "For You" page, introduced MLOps best practices
- Launched a self-paced, ML-focused coding training website to standardize and improve code quality across Deloitte NSE
- Centralized large-scale model storage, experiment tracking across various environments for a German steel conglomerate

Research Thesis Intern

Crunchr

₩ Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Amsterdam, Netherlands

At a people analytics platform, I conducted graph-based representation learning research for the development of ML products:

- Built a proof of concept, one-off representation learning process to encode relational database entity information
- Demonstrated approach validity by applying deep neural networks to downstream classification tasks on process outputs

Computer Vision Intern

Cubelizer

multiple image is a second in the second in

Madrid, Spain

As part of a Google-backed edge computer vision startup, I improved customer detection 12% in retail space optimization:

- Developed a video stream-based object detection method in compliance with EU privacy regulations
- Applied image processing and classical machine learning techniques to low-resolution images

PROJECTS

Python Machine Learning Template

- Automated a comprehensive Python ML project setup process with a project template and 3 simple bash commands
- Enabled streamlined project creation with pre-built tests, an automated build process, and auto-generated documentation

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence

University of Amsterdam

🗎 Sept 2018 - Dec 2020

- Amsterdam, Netherlands
- Courses on AI, including Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing, and Reinforcement Learning
- Thesis on "Interpretable Representation Learning for Relational Data" in collaboration with Crunchr
- Cum laude (8.0/10.0)

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering

The College of New Jersey

math Sept 2014 - May 2018

- **♀** Ewing, New Jersey, USA
- Met national engineering standards by passing the Fundamentals of Engineering Other Disciplines Exam
- Magna cum laude (3.8/4.0)

Study Abroad, Fine Arts & Art History

Anglo-American University

May 2016 - June 2016

- Prague, Czech Republic
- Intensive two-month study abroad in photography, art history
- Final grade: 4.0/4.0

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization

DeepLearning.Al

① Curriculum

% Certificate

SKILLS

Programming languages & tooling

Python, Git (2016-present), SQL (2019-present), C++ (2015-2016), Docker (2022-present), Kubernetes (2023-present)

MLOps platforms

Amazon Web Services (2021-present), Google Cloud Platform (2022-present), Databricks (2022-present), Azure DevOps Platform (2021-present)

ML frameworks

PyTorch (2018-present), PySpark (2022-present), FastAPI (2021-present), Tensorflow (2021-2022), Keras (2022)

Languages



Spanish



German



Russian